<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Briefe of the bill exhibited against bankrupts</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1624</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 9 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A03527</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 1365.5</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S1421</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">20178544</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 20178544</idno>
            <idno type="VID">23684</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A03527)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 23684)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1701:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A Briefe of the bill exhibited against bankrupts</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 broadside.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1624?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by STC (2nd ed.)</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bankruptcy --  England --  Law and legislation.</term>
               <term>Bankruptcy --  England --  Criminal provisions.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:23684:1"/>
            <head>A Briefe of the Bill exhibited againſt Bankrupts.</head>
            <p>THe Bill extendeth onely to make ſuch Bankrupts as ſeeke their liuing by buying and ſelling, as the former acts did, onely it maketh a Scriuener, receiuing o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
mens monyes into his truſt or cuſtody, lyable to the ſame, and an alien. It further deſcribeth a Bankrupt, and prouideth that the remedies appointed by the
former acts of 13. <hi>Eliza.</hi> and 1. <hi>Iac.</hi> ſhall be extended to ſuch as are deſcribed by this act to be Bankrupt. It enlargeth the remedies in ſome caſes, not ſufficiently
prouided for by the former lawes, and in ſpeciall caſes inflicteth corporall puniſhment.</p>
            <list>
               <item>It enlargeth the deſcription of a
Bankerupt, and addeth to the for<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>mer
Lawes.
<list>
                     <item>1. Such as ſhall obtaine or ſeeke protections againſt
Creditors, vnleſſe onely in time of Parliament.</item>
                     <item>2. Such as ſhall prefer or exhibit into any his Maieſties
Courts, any bill or bils, or to his Maieſty any petition, or
petitions of conformity, to compell Creditors take leſſe,
the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> their iuſt debts, or to procure longer daies of paiment.
<list>
                           <head>Reaſons.</head>
                           <item>1. Experience ſheweth, that this is done onely to delay and
hinder Creditors.</item>
                           <item>2. That they ſpend, and conſume their eſtates in the meane time.</item>
                           <item>3. The money ſpent in this courſe, and giuen to vndertakers,
may helpe pay his iuſt debts.</item>
                           <item>4. This is by pretence of a courſe of Law, to hinder Law.</item>
                           <item>5. This is to compell charity, which ſhould be free.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>3. Such as owing an hundred pound or more, ſhall
not pay or compound for the ſame, within ſixe moneths
after the ſame <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> grow <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> be demanded.
<list>
                           <item>1. Many men auoyd the acts which make a Bankrupt, but
make no conſcience by delayes to defraud men of their iuſt debts.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>4. Such as being arreſted for debt, ſhall lye in priſon
ſixe moneths, or being arreſted for two hundred pound
iuſt debt, or more, ſhall get forth by putting in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon
or hyred bayle, in which caſe the party is to be a
Bankrupt, from the time of the arreſt.
<list>
                           <item>1. Not being a Bankrupt til ſix moneths, incourageth Bankrupts,
in which time they prouide for their allies and friends at pleaſure.</item>
                           <item>2. They pay whom they liſt, they learne much ill and craft.</item>
                           <item>3. The common and hyred bayle, is a tricke meerely to defraud
Creditors, and a great abuſe.</item>
                           <item>4. After ſuch bayle, they keepe their perſons priuat, and yet ſpend
their eſtates.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
               <item>The Bil relieueth Creditors in ſome
caſes, not ſufficiently, or expreſly
prouided for by the former lawes.
<list>
                     <item>1. That the Bankrupts wife, after he is proued a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt,
ſhall and may be examined, onely for the diſcouery
of his eſtate, conueyed or concealed by her, and being in
her priuity.
<list>
                           <item>For want of this, the former lawes are of ſmall vſe for the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt,
knowing the wiues are not to be examined; conuay their
goods by their wiues helpe to perſons vnknowne to themſelues,
or any others then their wiues.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>2. That the Commiſſioners, or others by their war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant
or appoyntment, may breake open the Bankrupts
ſhop, houſe, or ware-houſe, to the intent to ſeaze his bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy,
goods, and eſtate.
<list>
                           <item>This is doubted, whether ſufficiently prouided for by the
former lawes, wherevpon ſome fearefull Commiſſioners, making
ſcruple, the Bankrupt in the meane time conuaieth away himſelfe,
and his goods at pleaſure.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>3. That for the better diſtributing of the Bankrupts
eſtate, the Commiſſioners may examine Creditors, vpon
the certainty of their iuſt debts, and that they be relieued
for no more then their meere debt, whatſoeuer ſecurity
they haue, by iudgement, ſtatute, recogniſance, or bond
forfeited, without reſpect to the penalties in ſuch ſecuri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties.
<list>
                           <item>This is not expreſly prouided for by the former lawes, but is
within the intent and equity, and is ſo done <hi>de facto,</hi> by Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>miſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners:
but the not expreſſing thereof, doth breed many times much
queſtion, and ſometimes ſuits in law, ſome Creditors requiring re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liefe
for penalties and forfeitures.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>4. That in caſe of any lands, goods, chattels, &amp;c. of
the Bankrupts, made ouer to any perſon, vpon condition
of redemption at a day, not due at the time of his being
a Bankrupt, the Commiſſioners may aſſigne power to any
perſons to pay the meere debt; vpon tender or payment
whereof, the Commiſſioners may deuide the ſurpluſage
of the benefit of the ſaid lands, goods, &amp;c.
<list>
                           <item>1. It hath been conceiued, the Commiſſioners haue not power
by the law, to aſſigne perſons to performe the condition, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vpon
the Creditors are forced to long and tedious ſuits, in Courts
of equity.</item>
                           <item>2. It ſeemeth very reaſonable and equall to be ſo.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>5. That in caſe of extents vpon any the Bankrupts
lands, goods, and chattels, by any accomptant to his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſty,
the Commiſſioners may examine ſuch accomptant
vpon oath, whether the debt were originally due to him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe,
or transferred to him in truſt for the vſe and benefit
of the party, whoſe debt it was: and if it were, that the
ſame be made ſubiect to the Commiſſion.
<list>
                           <item>It hath beene a vſuall courſe of late yeeres, to transferre debts to
accomptants, and to extend for his Maieſty, the accomptants
being onely vſed for other men, and yet the accomptants re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe
to anſwere vpon oath, to any ſuch interrogatory, becauſe it
ſeemeth to be the Kings caſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>6. That where lands, goods, or chattels, of any Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt,
be aſſigned ouer vpon good conſideration, yet the
ſame remaining in the poſſeſſion, order and diſpoſition of
the Bankrupt, after ſuch grant or gift made to receiue the
rents, and take the profits: That ſuch lands, goods, and
chattels be made ſubiect to the Commiſſion.
<list>
                           <item>This poſſeſſion of the Bankrupt, the grant being concealed, was
the motiue of the Bankrupts great truſt and credit.</item>
                           <item>This poſſeſſion of the Bankrupt, is a badge of fraud, and lyeth in
the deck many yeeres thus concealed.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
               <item>The Bill inflicteth corporall pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment,
by ſtanding on the Pillo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry
in the County, &amp;c. two houres,
and loſing one care by courſe of
indictment in caſes,
<list>
                     <item>1. Where the Bankrupt doth fraudulently, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceitfully
conuey away his goods, or chattels, to the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue
of fiue pound, and ſhall not vpon his oath diſcouer,
and (if it be in his power,) deliuer vnto the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners
all that eſtate, goods, and chattels ſo by him or his
meanes kept from the Commiſſioners.</item>
                     <item>2. Where hee cannot make it appeare vnto the
Commiſſioners, that he hath ſuſtayned ſome caſuall loſſe,
after the buying, and taking vp of ſuch wares, monyes
and commodities, whereby he is become vnable to pay
his iuſt debts.
<list>
                           <item>1. Bankrupts increaſe, and trade decreaſeth: the beſt remedy
will be feare of corporall puniſhment.</item>
                           <item>2. This corporall puniſhment is onely in caſe of wilfull fraud
and deceit, and where that fraud and deceit doth continue after
monition and warning by the Commiſſioners.</item>
                           <item>3. The trade of Bankrupting, is the worme that eateth out the
heart of all commerce and trade.</item>
                           <item>4. Without caſuall loſſe it is a wilfull wrong.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
               <item>The Bill appointeth the Bankrupt
to be purſued, and taken as a Felon,
and to ſuffer death as in caſe of felo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny,
without corruption of blood, or
forfeiture of lands, or goods in caſe,
<list>
                     <item>The Bankrupt ſhall flee away, and will not appeare
before the Commiſſioners, vpon or before the fift pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamation
to be made according to the forme of the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid
ſtatutes, and after three ſummons firſt made in
writing, vnder the Commiſſioners hands, and left at the
houſe, or ſhop, of the Bankrupts laſt abode or dwelling.
<list>
                           <item>1. This wilfull deceit is worſe then burglary, or robbing by
the high-way, which may be preuented, this cannot.</item>
                           <item>2. The time limited is very ſufficient for ſuch to come in and
auoyd this puniſhment.</item>
                           <item>3. This is more in terror to them, then likely to be proſecuted
by the Creditors.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
